<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ryu.clinic/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ryu.clinic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-12-17T12:24:59-08:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ryu Clinic Port Moody</title><subtitle>Acupuncture, RMT &amp; Herbal Medicine in Port Moody. ICBC, Acupuncture, RMT, TEM Herbal Medicine, Massage Therapy, Cupping, Pain Clinic, Rehabilitation, Acupoint Injection, Chronic Pain, Port Moody, Coquitlam, Tri-Cities, 한의원, 한약, 비염, 호흡기, 수면장애, 소화불량, 통증클리닉, 침치료, 포트무디</subtitle><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><entry><title type="html">Protocol for Psychiatric Disorders</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/treatment/protocol-for-psychiatric-disorders/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protocol for Psychiatric Disorders" /><published>2020-10-15T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-15T17:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/treatment/protocol-for-psychiatric-disorders</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/treatment/protocol-for-psychiatric-disorders/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-steps-approach&quot;&gt;3 Steps approach&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have 3 steps approaching method for diagnosis of symptoms. We decide a formula through our protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read personal characteristic and emotional status.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check sleeping quality and digestion &amp;amp; bowl movement conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify the trigger episode that caused the mental problem, read the propensity and approaches by synthesizing the physical symptoms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theses four conditions are the most important points of the protocol for phychiatric disorders: &lt;strong&gt;1) Sleeping quality 2) Characteristics 3) Emotions 4) Digestive system (especially bowel movement condition)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We try to introduce a direction of treatment to our body with balancing these four basic factors by checking with 3 steps approaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 3 steps approaching by detail anlysis, we can find the personalized treatment method. The keypoint of our treatment protocol is not only find problem in our brain but also in our body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><category term="Treatment" /><summary type="html">3 Steps approach</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Things To Know About Massage Therapy for Health Purposes</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/6-things-to-know-about-massage-therapy-for-health-purposes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Things To Know About Massage Therapy for Health Purposes" /><published>2020-08-31T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-31T17:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/6-things-to-know-about-massage-therapy-for-health-purposes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/6-things-to-know-about-massage-therapy-for-health-purposes/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;6-things-to-know-about-massage-therapy-for-health-purposes-&quot;&gt;6 Things To Know About Massage Therapy for Health Purposes &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “massage therapy” includes many techniques, and the type of massage given usually depends on your needs and physical condition. In general, massage therapists work on muscle and other soft tissue to help you feel better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the scientific research on massage therapy is preliminary or conflicting, but much of the evidence points toward beneficial effect on pain and other symptoms associated with a number of different conditions. Here are six things you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evidence suggests that massage therapy may be useful for some pain conditions such as low-back pain and chronic neck pain.&lt;/strong&gt; However, research on massage for headaches is preliminary and only somewhat promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research has suggested that at least for the short-term, massage therapy for cancer patients may reduce pain.&lt;/strong&gt; Evidence has suggested that massage therapy may also promote relaxation and boost mood in people with cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A recent review of scientific literature concluded that massage therapy may help to reduce depression.&lt;/strong&gt; However, a 2013 review found there is not enough evidence to determine if massage helps pregnant mothers with depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A 2010 review concluded that massage therapy may help temporarily reduce pain, fatigue, and other symptoms associated with fibromyalgia, but the evidence is not definitive.&lt;/strong&gt; The authors of the review noted that it is important that the massage therapist not cause pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Several studies on massage therapy in preterm infants have been conducted to determine if therapeutic massage provides any benefits.&lt;/strong&gt; A 2010 review of the scientific literature suggested that massaging preterm infants using moderate pressure may improve weight gain. However, a 2013 review determined that there is not enough evidence to know if massage benefits healthy infants who are developing normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massage therapy appears to have few risks when performed by a trained practitioner.&lt;/strong&gt; However, massage therapists should take some precautions with certain health conditions. You should talk with your health care providers to determine if massage therapy is safe for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/tips/things-to-know-about-massage-therapy-for-health-purposes &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><category term="Treatment" /><summary type="html">6 Things To Know About Massage Therapy for Health Purposes 1 The term “massage therapy” includes many techniques, and the type of massage given usually depends on your needs and physical condition. In general, massage therapists work on muscle and other soft tissue to help you feel better. https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/tips/things-to-know-about-massage-therapy-for-health-purposes &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Massage Therapy Overview</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/treatment/massage-therapy-overview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Massage Therapy Overview" /><published>2020-08-31T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-31T17:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/treatment/massage-therapy-overview</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/treatment/massage-therapy-overview/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;massage-therapy-what-you-need-to-know-&quot;&gt;Massage Therapy: What You Need To Know &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-massage-therapy-used-for&quot;&gt;What is massage therapy used for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massage therapy is used to help manage a health condition or enhance wellness. It involves manipulating the soft tissues of the body. Massage has been practiced in most cultures, both Eastern and Western, throughout human history, and was one of the earliest tools that people used to try to relieve pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-different-types-of-massage&quot;&gt;What are the different types of massage?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “massage therapy” includes many techniques. The most common form of massage therapy in Western countries is called Swedish or classical massage; it is the core of most massage training programs. Other styles include sports massage, clinical massage to accomplish specific goals such as releasing muscle spasms, and massage traditions derived from Eastern cultures, such as Shiatsu and Tuina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-massages-help-pain&quot;&gt;Do massages help pain?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massage therapy has been studied for several types of pain, including low-back pain, neck and shoulder pain, pain from osteoarthritis of the knee, and headaches. Here’s what the science says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;low-back-pain&quot;&gt;Low-Back Pain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several evaluations of massage for low-back pain have found only weak evidence that it may be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, in a 2016 evaluation of nondrug therapies for low-back pain, examined 20 studies that compared massage to usual care or other interventions and found that there was evidence that massage was helpful for chronic low-back pain but the strength of the evidence was low. The agency also looked at six studies that compared different types of massage but found that the evidence was insufficient to show whether any types were more effective than others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2015 review of 25 studies with a total of 3,096 participants found that in both acute and chronic low-back pain, there were short-term improvements in pain after massage therapy. However, because the quality of the studies was low, the investigators who conducted the review concluded that they had “very little confidence” that massage is an effective treatment for low-back pain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clinical practice guidelines (guidance for health care providers) issued by the American College of Physicians in 2017 included massage therapy as an option for treating acute/subacute low-back pain but did not include massage therapy among the options for treating chronic low-back pain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;neck-and-shoulder-pain&quot;&gt;Neck and Shoulder Pain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Massage therapy may be helpful for neck or shoulder pain, but the benefits may only last for a short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2013 review of 12 studies (757 total participants) found that massage therapy was more helpful for both neck and shoulder pain than inactive therapies but was not more effective than other active therapies. For shoulder pain, massage therapy had short-term benefits only.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2016 review of 4 studies conducted in the United States (519 participants) found that massage could provide short-term relief of neck pain if massage sessions were long enough and frequent enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;osteoarthritis-of-the-knee&quot;&gt;Osteoarthritis of the Knee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The small amount of research that’s been done on massage therapy for osteoarthritis of the knee suggests that it may have short-term benefits in relieving knee pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Of 6 studies that evaluated massage therapy for osteoarthritis of the knee (408 total participants), 5 found that it provided short-term pain relief. Two of the studies that showed pain relief (149 participants) involved the use of essential oils (aromatherapy massage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/arthritis/osteoarthritis&quot;&gt;NCCIH’s fact sheet on osteoarthritis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;headaches&quot;&gt;Headaches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only a small number of studies of massage for headache have been completed. These studies looked at different types of massage and different types of headache, and their results are not consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2016 study with 64 participants evaluated 2 types of massage (lymphatic drainage and traditional massage), once a week for 8 weeks, in patients with migraine. The frequency of migraines decreased in both groups, compared with people on a waiting list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a 2015 study, 56 people with tension headaches were assigned to receive massage at myofascial trigger points or an inactive treatment (detuned ultrasound) twice a week for 6 weeks or to be on a waiting list. People who received either massage or the inactive treatment had a decrease in the frequency of headaches, but there was no difference between the two groups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2011 study evaluated the effect of adding hand massage to multimodal behavior treatment of migraine in 83 people. Hand massage had no effect on migraine frequency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/pain/headachefacts.htm&quot;&gt;NCCIH’s fact sheet on headaches&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-massage-help-cancer-patients&quot;&gt;Can massage help cancer patients?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With appropriate precautions, massage therapy can be part of supportive care for cancer patients who would like to try it; however, the evidence that it can relieve pain and anxiety is not strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Massage therapy, with or without aromatherapy (the use of essential oils) has been used to attempt to relieve pain, anxiety, and other symptoms in people with cancer. A 2016 evaluation of 19 studies (more than 1,200 participants) of massage for cancer patients found some evidence that massage might help with pain and anxiety, but the quality of the evidence was very low (because most studies were small and some may have been biased), and findings were not consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clinical practice guidelines (guidance for health care providers) for the care of breast cancer patients include massage as one of several approaches that may be helpful for stress reduction, anxiety, depression, fatigue, and quality of life. Clinical practice guidelines for the care of lung cancer patients suggest that massage therapy could be added as part of supportive care in patients whose anxiety or pain is not adequately controlled by usual care.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Massage therapists may need to modify their usual techniques when working with cancer patients; for example, they may have to use less pressure than usual in areas that are sensitive because of cancer or cancer treatments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/cancer/complementary-integrative-research&quot;&gt;NCCIH’s fact sheet on cancer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-massage-be-helpful-for-fibromyalgia-symptoms&quot;&gt;Can massage be helpful for fibromyalgia symptoms?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massage therapy may be helpful for some fibromyalgia symptoms if it’s continued for long enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2014 evaluation of 9 studies (404 total participants) concluded that massage therapy, if continued for at least 5 weeks, improved pain, anxiety, and depression in people with fibromyalgia but did not have an effect on sleep disturbance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2015 evaluation of 10 studies (478 total participants) compared the effects of different kinds of massage therapy and found that most styles of massage had beneficial effects on quality of life in people with fibromyalgia. Swedish massage may be an exception; 2 studies of this type of massage (56 total participants) did not show benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/pain/fibromyalgia.htm&quot;&gt;NCCIH’s fact sheet on fibromyalgia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-massage-therapy-be-helpful-for-people-with-hivaids&quot;&gt;Can massage therapy be helpful for people with HIV/AIDS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s some evidence that massage therapy may have benefits for anxiety, depression, and quality of life in people with HIV/AIDS, but the amount of research and number of people studied are small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Massage therapy may help improve the quality of life for people with HIV or AIDS, a 2010 review of 4 studies with a total of 178 participants concluded.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More recently, a 2013 study of 54 people indicated that massage may be helpful for depression in people with HIV, and a 2017 study of 29 people with HIV suggested that massage may be helpful for anxiety.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-massage-help-baby-growth&quot;&gt;Does massage help baby growth?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s evidence that premature babies who are massaged may have improved weight gain. No benefits of massage for normal full-term infants have been clearly demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2017 research review analyzed the results of 34 studies of massage therapy for premature infants. Twenty of the studies (1,250 total infants) evaluated the effect of massage on weight gain, with most showing an improvement. The mechanism by which massage therapy might increase weight gain is not well understood. Some studies suggested other possible benefits of massage but because the amount of evidence is small, no conclusions can be reached about effects other than weight gain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2013 review of 34 studies of healthy full-term infants didn’t find clear evidence of beneficial effects of massage in these low-risk infants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-risks-of-massage-therapy&quot;&gt;What are the risks of massage therapy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risk of harmful effects from massage therapy appears to be low. However, there have been rare reports of serious side effects, such as a blood clot, nerve injury, or bone fracture. Some of the reported cases have involved vigorous types of massage, such as deep tissue massage, or patients who might be at increased risk of injury, such as elderly people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-requirements-to-become-a-massage-therapist&quot;&gt;What are the requirements to become a massage therapist?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In states that regulate massage therapy (45 states and the District of Columbia), therapists must get a license or certification before practicing massage. State regulations typically require graduation from an approved program and passing an examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some massage therapists obtain certification from the National Certification Board for Therapeutic Massage &amp;amp; Bodywork. To do this, they must meet specific educational requirements, undergo a background check, and pass an examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nccih-funded-research&quot;&gt;NCCIH-Funded Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NCCIH-sponsored studies have investigated various aspects of massage therapy, including&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether massage therapy can be helpful in preventing and treating repetitive motion disorders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If massage can be helpful as a component of a nondrug approach to pain management in veterans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If massage therapy can target sensory pathways that can help people with ankle sprains avoid chronic ankle instability (which can affect as many as 40 percent of people who experience this type of injury).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-to-consider&quot;&gt;Tips To Consider&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t use massage therapy to postpone seeing a health care provider about a medical problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re unsure whether massage therapy would be appropriate for you, discuss your concerns with your health care provider, who may also be able to help you select a massage therapist.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask about the training, experience, and credentials of the massage therapist you are considering. Also ask about the number of treatments that might be needed, the cost, and insurance coverage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For more tips on finding a massage therapist or other complementary health practitioner, see NCCIH’s webpage &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/howtofind.htm&quot;&gt;How To Find a Complementary Health Practitioner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/massage-therapy-what-you-need-to-know &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><category term="Treatment" /><summary type="html">Massage Therapy: What You Need To Know 1 https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/massage-therapy-what-you-need-to-know &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to our new RMT Oliviah</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/welcome-to-our-new-rmt-oliviah/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to our new RMT Oliviah" /><published>2020-08-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/welcome-to-our-new-rmt-oliviah</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/welcome-to-our-new-rmt-oliviah/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;oliviah-rac-rmt&quot;&gt;Oliviah, R.Ac, R.M.T.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has been practicing many years of experience in Acupuncture. Recently she got a new license as a Registered Massage Therapist. She is registered in CMTBC&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has a passion for massage, Tui-na, and Acupressure before so she decided to add a new title. She understands different conditions well, so you can get the best massage therapy based on her knowledgeable diagnosis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-an-rmt&quot;&gt;What is an RMT?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMTBC&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; stated&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A registered massage therapist (RMT) in British Columbia is a health professional regulated by CMTBC under BC’s Health Professions Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants for registration with CMTBC have completed post-secondary education in clinical applications of health sciences in massage therapy settings, and must meet CMTBC’s rigorous entry-level requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RMTs are subject to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CMTBC’s Standards of Practice and Code of Ethics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The requirements of the Health Professions Act and regulations made under the Act.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standards of professional conduct.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CMTBC’s quality assurance program, which ensures ongoing professional currency and development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all regulated health professionals, RMTs must practice within their professional scope of practice.  For RMTs, this means providing primarily manual, hands-on treatment and assessment in accordance with the definition of “massage therapy” in the Massage Therapists Regulation.  Many modalities and treatments that may be considered acceptable in other jurisdictions are outside the scope of practice of massage therapy in British Columbia.  CMTBC has posted specific guidance on yoga instruction and on using terms such as “specialize in” or “advanced” to describe one’s practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmtbc.ca&quot;&gt;CMTBC, College of Massage Therapists of British Columbia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmtbc.ca/what-is-an-rmt/&quot;&gt;What is an RMT?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Oliviah Kim</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Oliviah, R.Ac, R.M.T.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 Suter Brook Winter Festival</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/2019-suter-brook-winter-festival/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 Suter Brook Winter Festival" /><published>2019-11-27T11:28:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-27T11:28:00-08:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/2019-suter-brook-winter-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/2019-suter-brook-winter-festival/">&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;We are sponsoring the 2019 Suter Brook Winter Festival.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a ride on the horse-drawn carriage, interact with festive mascots, grab a photo with Mr.&amp;amp;Mrs.Claus, and enjoy live ice carving and holiday music!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: Dec.5th 2019 4 pm - 7 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Suter Brook Village at Port Moody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2019-winter-festival.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Poster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">We are sponsoring the 2019 Suter Brook Winter Festival.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ICBC Motor Vehicle Accident Assessment and Treatment</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/icbc-motor-vehicle-accident-assessment-and-treatment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ICBC Motor Vehicle Accident Assessment and Treatment" /><published>2019-11-19T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T16:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/icbc-motor-vehicle-accident-assessment-and-treatment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/icbc-motor-vehicle-accident-assessment-and-treatment/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;we-do-direct-billing-icbc&quot;&gt;We do Direct Billing ICBC&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--success&quot;&gt;No doctor’s referral required&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--success&quot;&gt;No upfront payment required&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--success&quot;&gt;No extra charges at our clinic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;icbc-policy-changed-as-of-april-1-2019&quot;&gt;ICBC policy changed as of April 1, 2019&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From April 1, 2019, the ICBC ICBC Motor Vehicle Accident (MVA) Treatment System will be changed.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, if you come to the clinic with a claim number without the cumbersome pre-processing, you can start the acupuncture treatment immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within 12 weeks of the accident, you can get 12 pre-approved ICBC traffic accident treatments for a minor accident and your expenses are covered. Of course, in case of major injuries, you can receive additional treatment through the approval process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in a car accident, please do not delay and come directly to Ryu Clinic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is well known that Acupuncture treatment also helps to overcome acute / chronic pain treatment and trauma. It is very encouraging that the system will be changed so that various treatments can be selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.gov.bc.ca/releases/2018AG0092-002177&quot;&gt;New Regulation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.icbc.com/change/default.html&quot;&gt;ICBC Change&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="About" /><category term="News" /><summary type="html">We do Direct Billing ICBC</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Deserve It</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/you-deserve-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Deserve It" /><published>2019-10-31T12:55:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-31T12:55:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/you-deserve-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/you-deserve-it/">&lt;figure class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mareko-tamaleaa-u29A-hrVgJU-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;this is a placeholder image&quot; /&gt;
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
      This is a figure caption.

    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Do something nice for yourself today. 
You deserve a break. 
Self-care is how you take your power back.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of possible explanation for benefit of acupuncture and herbal medicine. But the people are not interested in the explanation of the medical approach. We already have too much about many things to care about in daily life. Just let me know about your concern or come to ask for help. No matter how small or big issues, all of your concerns are taken care of by our care staff. You just should do small good stuff for yourself today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#YouDeserveIt #SelfCare&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">This is a figure caption.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enjoy the Labour Day long weekend</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/2018-labour-day-notice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enjoy the Labour Day long weekend" /><published>2019-09-01T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-01T17:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/2018-labour-day-notice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/2018-labour-day-notice/">&lt;p&gt;In observance of Labor Day, our office will be closed on Monday (Sep.2)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">In observance of Labor Day, our office will be closed on Monday (Sep.2)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why is pain killer not effective for chronic pain?</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/why-is-pain-killer-not-effective-for-chronic-pain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is pain killer not effective for chronic pain?" /><published>2018-08-02T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T17:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/why-is-pain-killer-not-effective-for-chronic-pain</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/why-is-pain-killer-not-effective-for-chronic-pain/">&lt;h4 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;sections-in-this-article&quot;&gt;Sections in this article&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#overview&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-is-chronic-pain-classified&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-how-is-chronic-pain-classified&quot;&gt;How is chronic pain classified?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#treatment-of-chronic-pain-with-herbal-medicine&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-treatment-of-chronic-pain-with-herbal-medicine&quot;&gt;Treatment of chronic pain with Herbal medicine&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see this article 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theglobeandmail.com/opinion/article-theres-a-chronic-pain-crisis-in-canada-and-governments-must-address/&quot;&gt;There’s a chronic pain crisis in Canada, and governments must address it&lt;/a&gt;, chronic pain affects one in every five Canadians, or six million of us. It’s a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike acute pain, chronic pain is characterized by the inability to be solved by taking painkillers. NSAIDS, the most commonly used pain reliever in hospitals, is a medicine that works only for acute pain by inhibiting the enzyme that produces the painful substance to block the last state of inflammation and thereby relieve pain. It is meaningless to prescribe analgesics after the pain has already disappeared in the area where the tissue damage has been occurring for more than a month. Therefore, in the case of chronic pain, the pain medication is ineffective, but it is a reality that it is continuously prescribed. It is not effective and long-term use for more than 10 days increases the risk of cerebral infarction or myocardial infarction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-chronic-pain-classified&quot;&gt;How is chronic pain classified?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly when the pain is chronic, the response of the nervous system to the acute pain is affected by various factors including mental or social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronic pain is usually chronic nociceptive pain in which the pain signal continues in an injured tissue, and chronic neuropathic pain, which is no longer harmful but continues to be excited by pain conduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be categorized as chronic psychogenic pain, which is disturbed by the circuit that erases the pain memory for psychological reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, chronic pain is not exactly divided into these categories. In most cases, 2-3 kinds of pain are entangled to reveal complex patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, chronic pain is not a simple scheme that suffers from peripheral stimuli such as acute pain, but the pain changes in the spinal cord and brain, causing the pain to increase or change the way you feel the pain. To be more precise, the patient himself is making new pain in the spinal cord or brain, or healing the existing pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, appromimately 60-80% of individuals with an amputation experience phantom sensations in their amputated limb, and the majority of the sensations are painful. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This is the well-known case in nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;treatment-of-chronic-pain-with-herbal-medicine&quot;&gt;Treatment of chronic pain with Herbal medicine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In herbal medicine, most prescriptions lead to both physical and mental reactions. In other words, it works both on the body and on the mind. You can expect the spinal cord and brain to act to erase the deformed pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By taking herbal medicine, various systems such as inflammation of the body, microcirculation, moisture distribution, heat production including psychological state can be restored to normal and the result can be the pain disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of acute pain, treatment with herbal medicine increases effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not let any kind of pain, such as back pain, arthralgia, arthritis, rheumatism, shoulder pain, etc., become chronic, and choose a wise healing method after diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_limb &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Sections in this article</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2018 Summer Holiday Closing Notice</title><link href="https://ryu.clinic/2018-summer-holiday-notice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 Summer Holiday Closing Notice" /><published>2018-07-20T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T17:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://ryu.clinic/2018-summer-holiday-notice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryu.clinic/2018-summer-holiday-notice/">&lt;p&gt;Please be informed that we will be closed from July 23 to 28 due to the Summer Holiday Closing. Inquiries during holidays will be reply after July 30. Thank you for your understanding and continued support with us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Minimalist Medicine</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Please be informed that we will be closed from July 23 to 28 due to the Summer Holiday Closing. Inquiries during holidays will be reply after July 30. Thank you for your understanding and continued support with us.</summary></entry></feed>