<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/getting-started/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-09-12T12:19:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/getting-started/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Ryu Clinic | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Acupuncture &amp; Herbal Medicine in Port Moody</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">ICBC 교통사고 치료</title>
      <link href="/icbc-%EA%B5%90%ED%86%B5%EC%82%AC%EA%B3%A0%EC%B9%98%EB%A3%8C" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ICBC 교통사고 치료" />
      <published>2019-03-31T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2019-03-31T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/icbc-%EA%B5%90%ED%86%B5%EC%82%AC%EA%B3%A0%EC%B9%98%EB%A3%8C</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/icbc-%EA%B5%90%ED%86%B5%EC%82%AC%EA%B3%A0%EC%B9%98%EB%A3%8C">&lt;h3 id=&quot;2019년-4월-1일부로-바뀐-icbc-정책&quot;&gt;2019년 4월 1일부로 바뀐 ICBC 정책&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019년 4월 1일 부터 ICBC 교통사고 치료관련 제도가 바뀝니다.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 사고가 나면 가장 중요한 것이 만성으로 넘어가지 않도록 빠른 시간안에 치료를 시작하는 것입니다. 앞으로는 번거로운 사전 과정 없이 클레임 넘버만 가지고 클리닉으로 오시면 바로 한방치료를 시작하실 수 있습니다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;사고가 난 날로부터 12주 이내에는 Minor 한 사고의 경우 12회의 사전 승인된 ICBC 교통사고 치료를 받으실 수 있고 비용은 보험으로 처리됩니다. 물론 Major 부상인 경우는 이후에도 추가적으로 승인과정을 통해서 치료를 더 받으실 수 있습니다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;차량 사고의 경우 지체하지 마시고 바로 &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryu.clinic/contact&quot;&gt;Ryu Clinic&lt;/a&gt;으로 오셔서 상담하시면 되겠습니다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;한의 치료가 급성/만성 통증 치료와 사고 충격 트라우마를 극복하는데도 도움이 되는 것은 이미 잘 알려진 사실입니다. 이렇게 다양한 치료를 선택해서 받으실 수 있도록 제도가 바뀌는 건 매우 고무적인 일이라 하겠습니다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.gov.bc.ca/releases/2018AG0092-002177&quot;&gt;New Regulation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.icbc.com/change/default.html&quot;&gt;ICBC Change&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">2019년 4월 1일부로 바뀐 ICBC 정책</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Why is pain killer not effective for chronic pain?</title>
      <link href="/why-is-pain-killer-not-effective-for-chronic-pain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is pain killer not effective for chronic pain?" />
      <published>2018-08-02T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2018-08-02T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/why-is-pain-killer-not-effective-for-chronic-pain</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/why-is-pain-killer-not-effective-for-chronic-pain">&lt;h4 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;sections-in-this-article&quot;&gt;Sections in this article&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#overview&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-is-chronic-pain-classified&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-how-is-chronic-pain-classified&quot;&gt;How is chronic pain classified?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#treatment-of-chronic-pain-with-herbal-medicine&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-treatment-of-chronic-pain-with-herbal-medicine&quot;&gt;Treatment of chronic pain with Herbal medicine&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see this article 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theglobeandmail.com/opinion/article-theres-a-chronic-pain-crisis-in-canada-and-governments-must-address/&quot;&gt;There’s a chronic pain crisis in Canada, and governments must address it&lt;/a&gt;, chronic pain affects one in every five Canadians, or six million of us. It’s a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike acute pain, chronic pain is characterized by the inability to be solved by taking painkillers. NSAIDS, the most commonly used pain reliever in hospitals, is a medicine that works only for acute pain by inhibiting the enzyme that produces the painful substance to block the last state of inflammation and thereby relieve pain. It is meaningless to prescribe analgesics after the pain has already disappeared in the area where the tissue damage has been occurring for more than a month. Therefore, in the case of chronic pain, the pain medication is ineffective, but it is a reality that it is continuously prescribed. It is not effective and long-term use for more than 10 days increases the risk of cerebral infarction or myocardial infarction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-chronic-pain-classified&quot;&gt;How is chronic pain classified?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly when the pain is chronic, the response of the nervous system to the acute pain is affected by various factors including mental or social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronic pain is usually chronic nociceptive pain in which the pain signal continues in an injured tissue, and chronic neuropathic pain, which is no longer harmful but continues to be excited by pain conduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be categorized as chronic psychogenic pain, which is disturbed by the circuit that erases the pain memory for psychological reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, chronic pain is not exactly divided into these categories. In most cases, 2-3 kinds of pain are entangled to reveal complex patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, chronic pain is not a simple scheme that suffers from peripheral stimuli such as acute pain, but the pain changes in the spinal cord and brain, causing the pain to increase or change the way you feel the pain. To be more precise, the patient himself is making new pain in the spinal cord or brain, or healing the existing pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, appromimately 60-80% of individuals with an amputation experience phantom sensations in their amputated limb, and the majority of the sensations are painful. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This is the well-known case in nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;treatment-of-chronic-pain-with-herbal-medicine&quot;&gt;Treatment of chronic pain with Herbal medicine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In herbal medicine, most prescriptions lead to both physical and mental reactions. In other words, it works both on the body and on the mind. You can expect the spinal cord and brain to act to erase the deformed pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By taking herbal medicine, various systems such as inflammation of the body, microcirculation, moisture distribution, heat production including psychological state can be restored to normal and the result can be the pain disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of acute pain, treatment with herbal medicine increases effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not let any kind of pain, such as back pain, arthralgia, arthritis, rheumatism, shoulder pain, etc., become chronic, and choose a wise healing method after diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_limb &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Sections in this article</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Treatment Method</title>
      <link href="/treatment-method" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Treatment Method" />
      <published>2018-06-30T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2018-06-30T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/treatment-method</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/treatment-method">&lt;h1 id=&quot;acupoint-injection-therapy&quot;&gt;Acupoint Injection Therapy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ariabc.org.png&quot; alt=&quot;Acupoint and Regeneration Injection Association of BC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;auricular-acupuncture&quot;&gt;Auricular Acupuncture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ear is a microsystem which reflects the entire body. Conditions affecting the physical, mental or emotional health of the patient can be treatable by stimulating the surface of the ear with a small seed. It is also called auricular acupuncture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/earacu841x425jpeg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Auricular Acupuncture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cupping&quot;&gt;Cupping&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cupping is a therapy designed to stimulate the flow of blood and Qi within the superficial muscles layers. It is used for many ailments including sore muscles, tension, neck pain and the common cold. In the therapy, vacuumed glass or plastic “cups” will be placed over specific areas on your body. They may be moved to an affected area or left in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cupping.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cupping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;moxibustion&quot;&gt;Moxibustion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moxibustion is a treatment that uses an herb called mugwort. It may be burned on the handle of the needle, above the skin, directly on the skin, on salt or on a slice of ginger. This is used to “warm” acupuncture points or areas in order to quicken the healing process. We are also doing Japanese style of direct moxibustion: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.najom.org/&quot;&gt;North America Journal of Oriental Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/bl67AOA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moxibustion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tui-na&quot;&gt;Tui-Na&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!---
## Qigong Therapy
![image-left](//assets/images/qigong841x425jpeg.jpg){: .align-left}  Qigong therapy includes breathing, postures and/or movement. The therapy may be used during treatment or may be taught to patients who need posture correction, increase in energy level, muscle pain relief, and stress relief for regular practice.
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tui-na translates as “push grasp”. It is a massage technique that moves Qi in various parts of the body. It is used to relieve muscle pain, tension, and inflammation and to heal injuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tuina841x425jpeg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tui-Na&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Acupoint Injection Therapy</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">How to Prepare For and Receive Acupuncture</title>
      <link href="/how-to-prepare-for-and-receive-acupuncture" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Prepare For and Receive Acupuncture" />
      <published>2018-06-24T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2018-06-24T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/how-to-prepare-for-and-receive-acupuncture</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/how-to-prepare-for-and-receive-acupuncture">&lt;p&gt;Here is a good article for prepare and receive acupuncture from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikihow.com/Prepare-For-and-Receive-Acupuncture&quot;&gt;Wiki How&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s likely that you have heard of acupuncture, and you may even know someone who has experienced it. Acupuncture is the attempt to restore and maintain health through the stimulation of specific anatomical points on the body. It can be done either by a small needle or a laser.[1] If you’re considering trying this alternative medical system yourself, for a condition that is chronic, or one where Western medicine seems to have failed you, here are some ideas for approaching your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study the concept and system of Oriental acupuncture.&lt;/strong&gt;
Acupuncture has been used for thousands of years in China and Asia.[2] However, it doesn’t follow a Western European method of disease diagnosis and treatment, so it is useful to consider this as an alternative method to rectify your condition.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read about it in books or magazines.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talk to an acupuncture practitioner, or to someone who has successfully used it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read information on suitable websites, such as government health departments or traditional Chinese medicine schools with a good reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decide if you can trust or accept this methodology.&lt;/strong&gt;
If you are extremely adverse to trying it, no one can or should convince you to do so. However, if you are convinced it might work for you, or you’re feeling desperate for another treatment route, acupuncture might be extremely helpful and be exactly what you need. Acupuncture can relieve pain, reduce symptoms, or help restore balance to your body’s system. Only you can decide if it is worth giving it a try.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Be wary of anyone who claims it can cure anything more substantial, however, as it doesn’t cure cancer and cannot save you from an incurable illness.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Determine if your insurance plan will cover treatment.&lt;/strong&gt;
If you have decided to try acupuncture, see if it is covered by your insurance plan or your health system’s welfare coverage.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Your doctor might have to refer you for treatment to get it covered. Discuss this idea with your doctor first if you’d like.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If it’s not covered, decide if you can afford to pay out of pocket for it on your own. In case money is an issue search for a local “community style” acupuncturist who treats people in a group setting which cuts costs down on the cost of treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a qualified practitioner.&lt;/strong&gt;
Depending on where you live, you might easily find a qualified acupuncture doctor, or you may not. The NIH, however, has found that acupuncture is being widely practiced by physicians, dentists, acupuncturists, and other practitioners.[1] You will need to check if acupuncture is regulated where you live; a state, province, or region may or may not certify such doctors, making it harder for you to know whether or not your acupuncturist is reputable.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you are having difficulties finding out, inquire in a local Oriental medicine clinic or college for more information.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you know of people who have had successful treatments, ask for their recommendation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Always ask to see their credentials and state license.[1]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule your first consultation.&lt;/strong&gt;
Go to the acupuncturist and tell him/her your problem. Show your acupuncturist where your pain is, explain your symptoms, tell him/her what you’ve tried before, what you eat, how you sleep. Be open to the acupuncturist’s explanation and suggestions. Expect the explanation to be different from what a Western doctor may say.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand what the treatment consists of.&lt;/strong&gt;
Acupuncture is a system in which you receive a series of up to 20 treatments of up to an hour each (or more), spread out over several weeks. There will usually be a day or two between each treatment or possibly a week depending on your condition. Acupuncture focuses on treating overall well-being and not just the symptoms, taking a holistic approach. This means you must set aside time because it is useless to take only one treatment, or to begin a series and not finish it. Not finishing a course of treatment is a waste of money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare for your first treatment.&lt;/strong&gt;
Tell the acupuncturist if this is your first time. He/she will probably explain what is going on in more detail for a new patient. Normally, you will lie on a regular examination or massage bed, and remove clothes from the areas the acupuncturist tells you to. You will be draped in a sheet or towel, plus a blanket if it’s cold. Be sure to wear loose clothing when you go for your appointment.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The acupuncturist will unwrap brand new never used sterile needles from plastic packets. They might also swab the insertion areas with alcohol (this is required for qualified acupuncturists in the USA). You might not see where they will be inserted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relax.&lt;/strong&gt;
Close your eyes and let your muscles loosen. This is a time to focus your energy inward toward healing. Focus on the fact that you have pain or something wrong, and you want to get better. Let this happen.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You will feel a small prick when the needle is inserted. After that first instant, you should feel nothing. If you feel a sudden sharp nerve pain, alert the acupuncturist to let him or her know. He/she might need to remove the needle and insert it in a slightly different place.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The acupuncturist may insert up to 20 different needles at various points, though the first treatment may have fewer. Lie still. Close your eyes. Relax. Visualize the areas of pain or problems, and how they must improve. You should soon feel absolutely nothing. Rest. Take a little nap. Meditate.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pain is subjective, and many people report no or minimal pain from acupuncture.[1] If there is undue pain, alert the practitioner immediately as it may be the result of improper placement of the needles, a defective needle, or your own movement causing a slip.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lie quietly for the duration of treatment.&lt;/strong&gt;
This could be anywhere from 20-60 minutes, less at first. Don’t plan to read, though you could listen to quiet music. It’s best to simply snooze or meditate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t fight the treatment.&lt;/strong&gt;
You have decided to receive acupuncture. Now you must relax, not argue, or stress. Otherwise it won’t work as well. Go with it. If you decide later not to return, that’s your choice. During the treatment, simply lie there. It won’t hurt after the first moment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to relax after the treatment because your muscles need to rest.&lt;/strong&gt;
Bruising is normal if you had needles inserted into you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Here is a good article for prepare and receive acupuncture from Wiki How</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">What Is Community Acupuncture?</title>
      <link href="/what-is-community-acupuncture" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Is Community Acupuncture?" />
      <published>2018-06-13T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2018-06-13T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/what-is-community-acupuncture</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/what-is-community-acupuncture">&lt;h4 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;sections-in-this-article&quot;&gt;Sections in this article&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-short-version-&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-short-version-&quot;&gt;The Short Version &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#for-the-long-version-read-here&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-for-the-long-version-read-here&quot;&gt;For The Long Version, read here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-can-you-afford-to-charge-so-little-to-community-acupuncture&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-how-can-you-afford-to-charge-so-little-to-community-acupuncture&quot;&gt;How can you afford to charge so little to community acupuncture?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#do-i-have-to-take-my-clothes-off-for-community-acupuncture-treatment&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-do-i-have-to-take-my-clothes-off-for-community-acupuncture-treatment&quot;&gt;Do I have to take my clothes off for community acupuncture treatment?&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-short-version-&quot;&gt;The Short Version &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We define Community Acupuncture as the practice of offering acupuncture:
1) in a setting where multiple patients receive treatments at the same time;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) by financially sustainable and accountable means, whereby community acupuncture clinics depend directly on the support of the people who receive acupuncture in them, rather than on grants, donations, or other funding;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) within a context of accessibility, which we create by providing consistent hours, by making frequent treatments readily available, by offering affordable services, and by lowering all the barriers to treatment that we possibly can, for as many people as we possibly can, while continuing to be financially self-sustaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-long-version-read-here&quot;&gt;For The Long Version, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pocacoop.com/what-is-ca-long-answer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-you-afford-to-charge-so-little-to-community-acupuncture&quot;&gt;How can you afford to charge so little to community acupuncture?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we treat lots of people.  What’s most important to a community acupuncturist is simply to give many people the chance to receive treatments. Likewise, the business needs to see many people in order to make ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plainly said, we want acupuncture to be readily available as a means to help take care of the health of our neighbors and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-i-have-to-take-my-clothes-off-for-community-acupuncture-treatment&quot;&gt;Do I have to take my clothes off for community acupuncture treatment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely not.  Occasionally, we may need to have access to areas just above the knee or up to the shoulder joint, in which case we’d ask you to wear shorts or a tee shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But by and large all it takes to get ready for treatment is to roll up pant legs and shirt sleeves, as points on the lower arms and legs are the most commonly used in community clinics.  No need to take any other clothes off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://www.pocacoop.com/faq &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Sections in this article</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Prolotherapy Overview</title>
      <link href="/prolotherapy-overview" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prolotherapy Overview" />
      <published>2018-05-21T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2018-05-21T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/prolotherapy-overview</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/prolotherapy-overview">&lt;h4 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;sections-in-this-article&quot;&gt;Sections in this article&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prolotherapy-overview&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-prolotherapy-overview&quot;&gt;Prolotherapy Overview&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-first-stage-is-inflammation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-first-stage-is-inflammation&quot;&gt;The first stage is inflammation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-second-stage-is-proliferation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-second-stage-is-proliferation&quot;&gt;The second stage is proliferation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-third-stage-is-the-remodeling-phase&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-third-stage-is-the-remodeling-phase&quot;&gt;The third stage is the remodeling phase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#relevance-to-clinical-outcomes&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-relevance-to-clinical-outcomes&quot;&gt;Relevance to clinical outcomes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prolotherapy-overview&quot;&gt;Prolotherapy Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prolotherapy, also called proliferation therapy or regenerative injection therapy is a treatment of tissue with the injection of an irritant solution into a joint space, weakened ligament, or tendon insertion to relieve pain. The term Proli is Latin for “to grow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most commonly injected irritant solution used is dextrose, which is another name for glucose (sugar).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand why this is done, we have to look at the supporting structures of a joint.
Tendon vs Ligament&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, muscles attach to bone through a tough band of fibrous connective tissue called a tendon, which is made up of collagen. Ligaments attach bone to bone and are also made up of collagen to form a fibrous connective tissue. These tissues (tendons and ligaments) are the target of prolotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tendons and ligaments when compared to muscles have a poor blood supply and are therefore slower to heal and rebuild damaged collagen. However, prolotherapy can overcomes this limitation by injecting dextrose into the tendons and ligaments which stimulates a healing/repair response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body’s repair process moves through 3 stages, all of which are triggered in succession of each other by prolotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-stage-is-inflammation&quot;&gt;The first stage is inflammation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This occurs through a brief AA (arachidonic acid) pathway of inflammation.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; After an injury, the body uses primarily AA inflammation to try to repair the damage. With prolotherapy there is no significant damage, because there is no stretching or tearing of fibers, but the body still begins a repair process, which allows the structure to become stronger and tighter rather than first becoming weaker and looser. The inflammatory phase has a rapid onset (few hours at most) and swiftly increases in magnitude to its maximal reaction (1-3 days) before gradually resolving (over the next couple of weeks). It can result in several outcomes but in terms of tissue repair, it is normal and essential.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-second-stage-is-proliferation&quot;&gt;The second stage is proliferation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proliferative phase essentially involves the generation of the repair material, which for the majority of musculoskeletal injuries, involves the production of scar (type III collagen) material, although no scars are being produced by prolotherapy. The proliferative phase has a rapid onset (24-48 hours) but takes considerably longer to reach its peak reactivity, which is usually between 2-3 weeks post injury (the more vascular the tissue, the shorter the time taken to reach peak proliferative production). This peak in activity does not represent the time at which scar production (repair) is complete, but the time phase during which the bulk of the scar material (or in the case of prolotherapy, new collagen) is formed. The production of a final product (a stronger thicker tendon or ligament) is not achieved until later in the overall repair process. In general terms it is usually considered that proliferation runs from the first day or two post injury through to its peak at 2-3 weeks and decreases thereafter through to a matter of several months (typically 4-6) post trauma.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-third-stage-is-the-remodeling-phase&quot;&gt;The third stage is the remodeling phase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During remodelling, type III collagen, which is prevalent during proliferation, is replaced by type I collagen. Originally disorganized collagen fibers are rearranged, cross-linked, and aligned along tension lines. The onset of the remodelling phase may vary extensively, depending on the size of the injury, ranging from approximately 3 days to 3 weeks. The remodelling phase can last for a year or longer, similarly depending on the injury.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relevance-to-clinical-outcomes&quot;&gt;Relevance to clinical outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the slow speed at which the body goes through these stages, especially the remodelling phase, full benefits of prolotherapy may not be realized until months after treatment occurs. While benefits may be seen in the short term, one should not be discouraged if the problem is not resolved immediately after the first treatment, as several treatments are usually required due to the nature of tendons and ligaments having a poor blood supply. Expect 3-5 treatments over the course of 3-6 months to truly judge a benefit from the treatment. Although some patients only require 1-2 treatments and see immediate results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://www.clinicalradiologyonline.net/article/S0009-9260(10)00351-X/fulltext &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://www.drreeves.com/sites/default/files/How%20Injections%20Work,%20March%202014.pdf &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://www.electrotherapy.org/modality/soft-tissue-repair-and-healing-review &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wound_healing#Maturation_and_remodeling &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Sections in this article</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Acupoint Injection Overview</title>
      <link href="/acupoint-injection-overview" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acupoint Injection Overview" />
      <published>2018-05-21T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2018-05-21T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/acupoint-injection-overview</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/acupoint-injection-overview">&lt;h4 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;sections-in-this-article&quot;&gt;Sections in this article&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#acupoint-injection-overview&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-acupoint-injection-overview&quot;&gt;Acupoint Injection Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;acupoint-injection-overview&quot;&gt;Acupoint Injection Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ariabc.org.png&quot; alt=&quot;Acupoint injection therapy overview from [ARIABC](http://ariabc.org)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to famous TCM author Qiu Maoliang‘s most influential textbook, Chinese Acupuncture and Moxibustion; acupoint injection therapy is described as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…a method of injecting liquid medicine into acupoints in order to prevent and treat disease. It combines permeating and stimulating functions of needles and medicine, and can enhance both their therapeutic effects in treating disease.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupoint injection therapy also referred to as aquapuncture therapy was developed in China in the early 1950s&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and has been used in China ever since.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Acupoint injection therapy has a Western equivalent in trigger point injection therapy. Trigger points are described as hyperirritable spots in the fascia surrounding skeletal muscle. They are associated with palpable nodules in taut bands of muscle fibers.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many practitioners maintain that trigger points are separate entities from acupoints. However, ashi points, which are described in The Yellow Emperor’s Classic and are considered acupoints, exhibit pain upon palpation&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and demonstrate characteristics identical to the Western concept of trigger points. Research has demonstrated that, when comparing 255 known trigger points to known acupuncture points, 92% of trigger points had anatomically corresponding acupoints. Interestingly, the characteristics of their referred pain patterns had complete or near-complete agreement with 76% of their corresponding acupoints, with another 14% having at least some agreement.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important to note because many research studies have been conducted using the terms ‘acupoint injection’ and ‘trigger point injection’ without any major differences between actual methods used in the research. For this reason, we include research studies on trigger point injections along with research on acupoint injections in this article: they are identical concepts expressed under different names. Trigger point injection courses are taught around the world to many different practitioners, including medical doctors, naturopathic doctors, acupuncturists, and registered nurses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has revealed that acupoint injection/wet needling has advantages over acupuncture/dry needling. Injection is more practical and rapid, since it causes less disturbance during the procedure. It also results in lower pain scores and a higher pain pressure threshold, outperforming both acupuncture and botulinum toxin type A (botox injection).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Research demonstrates that acupoint injection results in significantly less post-injection soreness when compared to dry acupuncture when measured 2 to 8 hours after treatment.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While acupuncture points (acupoints) are the intended target of this therapy, the structures accessed during this procedure can range from cutanenous right down to the periosteum or articular cartilage and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Maoliang, Qiu. Subject Adviser‘s Preface, p. IX , and ―Point-Injection Therapy (hydro-acupuncture therapy), pp.220-222, in Chinese Acupuncture and Moxibustion (Churchill Livingstone: February 8, 1993). Available at http://www.amazon.com/Chinese-Acupuncture-Moxibustion-Mao-Liang-Qiu/dp/0443042233 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Fan A. Dry needling is acupuncture.” in Acupunct Med doi:10.1136/acupmed-2015-011010. http://aim.bmj.com/content/early/2015/12/15/acupmed-2015-011010.long &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Water Injection Therapy, The World Federation of Acupuncture-Moxibustion Societies. www.wfas.org.cn/tcmtools/therapy/835.html &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Travell J, Simons D &amp;amp; Lois S. Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, (LWW: 1998), p. 5. Available at http://www.amazon.com/Myofascial-Pain-Dysfunction-Trigger-Manual/dp/0683083635 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Nugent-Head, Andrew. Ashi Points in Clinical Practice‖ in Journal of Chinese Medicine 101 (February 2013), pp. 5-12. Accessed December 28, 2015 at https://www.jcm.co.uk/ashi-points-in-clinical-practice.html &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Dorsher, Peter T. MD. Trigger Points And Acupuncture Points: Anatomic And Clinical Correlations‖ in Medical Acupuncture Journal 17, Issue 3 (May 2006), pp. 20-23. http://myofascialtherapy.massagetherapy.com/trigger-points-and-acupuncture-points-medical-article &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Kamanli, A. ―Comparison of lidocaine injection, botulinum toxin injection, and dry needling to trigger points in myofascial pain syndrome in Rheumatology International 25, Issue 8 (October 2005), pp. 604-611. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15372199 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hong, CZ. ―Lidocaine injection versus dry needling to myofascial trigger point. The importance of the local twitch response. in American Journal of Physical Medicine &amp;amp; Rehabilitation 73, Issue 4 (July-August 1994), pp. 256-263. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8043247 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Sections in this article</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">FAQ</title>
      <link href="/faq" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FAQ" />
      <published>2017-04-04T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2017-04-04T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/faq</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/faq">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-acupuncture-do&quot;&gt;What Does Acupuncture Do?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;acupuncture-public-awareness-video&quot;&gt;Acupuncture Public Awareness Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- 16:9 aspect ratio --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/udak0DDgyek&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Association of Traditional Chinese Medicine and Acupuncture of British Columbia (ATCMA) shared a public awareness video about how acupuncture can improve the quality of life of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-acupuncture&quot;&gt;What Is Acupuncture?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of Traditional Chinese Medicine(TCM) Therapies is to recover the natural balance of your body by stimulating acupuncture points on the body. It can not only enhance recuperative power, immunity and physical and emotional health, but also improve overall function and well-being&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture activates the body’s Qi and promotes natural healing by using fine, sterile needles at specific acupoints in the body. It can not only enhance recuperative power, immunity and physical and emotional health but also improve overall function and well-being. It is a safe and effective way to treat a wide variety of medical problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/yintangAoA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image description&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-community-acupuncture&quot;&gt;What Is Community Acupuncture?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-short-version&quot;&gt;The Short Version&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We define Community Acupuncture as the practice of offering acupuncture:
1) in a setting where multiple patients receive treatments at the same time;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) by financially sustainable and accountable means, whereby community acupuncture clinics depend directly on the support of the people who receive acupuncture in them, rather than on grants, donations, or other funding;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) within a context of accessibility, which we create by providing consistent hours, by making frequent treatments readily available, by offering affordable services, and by lowering all the barriers to treatment that we possibly can, for as many people as we possibly can, while continuing to be financially self-sustaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-long-version-read-here&quot;&gt;For The Long Version, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pocacoop.com/what-is-ca-long-answer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-you-afford-to-charge-so-little-to-community-acupuncture&quot;&gt;How can you afford to charge so little to community acupuncture?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we treat lots of people.  What’s most important to a community acupuncturist is simply to give many people the chance to receive treatments. Likewise, the business needs to see many people in order to make ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plainly said, we want acupuncture to be readily available as a means to help take care of the health of our neighbors and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-i-have-to-take-my-clothes-off-for-community-acupuncture-treatment&quot;&gt;Do I have to take my clothes off for community acupuncture treatment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely not.  Occasionally, we may need to have access to areas just above the knee or up to the shoulder joint, in which case we’d ask you to wear shorts or a tee shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But by and large all it takes to get ready for treatment is to roll up pant legs and shirt sleeves, as points on the lower arms and legs are the most commonly used in community clinics.  No need to take any other clothes off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;do-needles-hurt&quot;&gt;Do Needles Hurt?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really much at all. However, getting an acupuncture treatment isn’t always painless. More than anything a treatment should be a deeply relaxing and sleepy slice of time for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we’d like our patients to know: You may feel a bit of a pinch when the needles are tapped in, but this should ease right away. If you continue to feel a pinching or a burning sensation at the needle site any longer than this, let us know. It means we haven’t placed that needle real well. If on the other hand you are feeling a slight ache or heavy feeling near the needle, this is usually a good sign – a clue that the body is reacting in a productive way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that as long as the feelings around the needled areas don’t keep you from closing your eyes and napping for a little while, we say let them be.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">What Does Acupuncture Do?</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Self Care After AcuPoint Injections</title>
      <link href="/self-care-after-acupoint-injections" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self Care After AcuPoint Injections" />
      <published>2015-08-03T17:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2015-08-03T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>/self-care-after-acupoint-injections</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/self-care-after-acupoint-injections">&lt;h4 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;sections-in-this-article&quot;&gt;Sections in this article&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-changes-have-occurred-in-my-body-as-a-result-of-the-injections&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-changes-have-occurred-in-my-body-as-a-result-of-the-injections&quot;&gt;What changes have occurred in my body as a result of the injections?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-will-the-discomfort-or-pain-be-like-afterwards&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-will-the-discomfort-or-pain-be-like-afterwards&quot;&gt;What will the discomfort or pain be like afterwards?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-long-will-post-injection-soreness-last&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-how-long-will-post-injection-soreness-last&quot;&gt;How long will post-injection soreness last?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-should-i-do-to-ease-discomfort-after-injections&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-should-i-do-to-ease-discomfort-after-injections&quot;&gt;What should I do to ease discomfort after injections?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#will-moist-heat-help&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-will-moist-heat-help&quot;&gt;Will moist heat help?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#will-ice-help&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-will-ice-help&quot;&gt;Will ice help?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#will-massaging-the-muscle-help&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-will-massaging-the-muscle-help&quot;&gt;Will massaging the muscle help?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#is-stretching-important&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-is-stretching-important&quot;&gt;Is stretching important?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-often-should-i-stretch&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-how-often-should-i-stretch&quot;&gt;How often should I stretch?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-if-i-dont-have-enough-time-to-stretch&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-if-i-dont-have-enough-time-to-stretch&quot;&gt;What if I don’t have enough time to stretch?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-if-i-have-too-much-pain-to-stretch&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-if-i-have-too-much-pain-to-stretch&quot;&gt;What if I have too much pain to stretch?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#when-should-i-call-my-doctor-for-an-emergency-visit&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-when-should-i-call-my-doctor-for-an-emergency-visit&quot;&gt;When should I call my doctor for an emergency visit?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#when-should-i-take-pain-medicine&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-when-should-i-take-pain-medicine&quot;&gt;When should I take pain medicine?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#should-i-get-other-bodywork&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-should-i-get-other-bodywork&quot;&gt;Should I get other bodywork?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have been given trigger point injections today. This information reviews what you can expect to feel, and reminds you of important things to do during the next few days in order to minimize your discomfort and get the best results possible from the treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-changes-have-occurred-in-my-body-as-a-result-of-the-injections&quot;&gt;What changes have occurred in my body as a result of the injections?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trigger point injections unlocked knots in the muscles and released a lot of the tension that was present in the injected muscles. Afterwards, these muscles were stretched to their normal length. The treated muscles should be softer than they were before treatment, range of motion may be increased, and the more serious pain should be lessened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-will-the-discomfort-or-pain-be-like-afterwards&quot;&gt;What will the discomfort or pain be like afterwards?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The areas of your body that were injected are likely to be sore. This soreness should be more like the discomfort you experience in your muscles after working out with weights, especially if you haven’t done it for a while and you lifted yesterday. There shouldn’t be “serious” pain in the injected areas. If discomfort is at this level, please call the doctor’s office first thing the next morning. If your injections were done in the morning and this level of pain is present in the early afternoon, please call the doctor’s office to see if you need to come back in that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-long-will-post-injection-soreness-last&quot;&gt;How long will post-injection soreness last?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually the soreness after injections will be very similar to the soreness that occurs the day after lifting weights. It typically will last 1 to 2 days, like the soreness after wight lifting. Occasionally people are sore for the week, but this is rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-should-i-do-to-ease-discomfort-after-injections&quot;&gt;What should I do to ease discomfort after injections?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First - drink water - when tension gets released from the muscle, blood can suddenly get in the muscle and cleanse it of toxins. You need to flush these toxins from your body. Drinking water hastens this process, and helps you avoid getting sick from the toxins. People who don’t drink enough water may experience fever, nausea, and general “flu- like” symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second - stretch often. A lot of generalized aching can be relieved with gentle lengthening(stretching). You need to keep the muscles from tightening back up. This may require stretching every 10 minutes sometimes, and during other parts of the day, every couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third - use the ball often. The muscles will appreciate a lot of gentle massaging. When the muscle are sore, use the ball gently and “Tender Loving Care”. There is no need to apply a lot of pressure and make it hurt more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-moist-heat-help&quot;&gt;Will moist heat help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moist heat should be applied to the injected area to soothe the tissue and help stretch the muscles further and more easily. Moist heat is more soothing and more easily applied in an even fashion than dry heat. You are encouraged to apply moist heat for 15-20 minutes at a time while you stretch. This should be done at least one or two times during the first evening after injections. It is also very important to stretch first thing in the morning under a hot shower. Consider applying moist heat even before stretching, especially if you are having a difficult time stretching and reducing the pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-ice-help&quot;&gt;Will ice help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ice helps some people. Ice will usually reduce pain and swelling. If you have swelling and a lot of pain after injections, try ice and see if it helps you. Some people like the ice to be as cold as possible. Others find it effective if the ice is insulated from the skin by cloth, so that it feels more comfortably cool than frozen cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-massaging-the-muscle-help&quot;&gt;Will massaging the muscle help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, gently massaging the injected muscles is not only helpful but very necessary. The massage helps increase blood flow to the area, and remove toxins. You will usually find the injected muscles to be tender to touch, so massage them often, and perhaps very gently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-stretching-important&quot;&gt;Is stretching important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, stretching and keeping the muscles from tightening is what will make you better. The injection is only the tool that your doctor used to make the muscle spasm release. It is up to you to keep the muscle stretched out towards its normal and healthy resting length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-often-should-i-stretch&quot;&gt;How often should I stretch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to stretch often enough to counteract the tendency of the injected muscles to tighten back up. Most people need to stretch at least once every hour during waking hours of the first day. Some people tighten quickly enough that they need to stretch parts of their bodies every 10 minutes for periods of time. By the third day, you should still be stretching the problem areas at least once every 3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-if-i-dont-have-enough-time-to-stretch&quot;&gt;What if I don’t have enough time to stretch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us have busy schedules and can’t imagine taking the time for moist heat and stretching every hour with the deep breathing technique that were taught. We found that the quantity (stretching often) is more important than how far you stretch. If you don’t have time to “stretch to completion”, with several relaxation breaths in each direction or with each position, then just do one or two breaths and only stretch the muscles that are giving you the most problem. These are the more important muscles to stretch anyway. Repetition of stretching is much more important than the length of time spent doing the exercises. Do not however, try to stretch as far in one or two breaths as you would in six. When time is short, stretch just as slowly, and don’t move as far. &lt;strong&gt;It is not as important to stretch further each time, it is more important to keep from tightening back up!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-if-i-have-too-much-pain-to-stretch&quot;&gt;What if I have too much pain to stretch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very rare. You might have too much pain to stretch far, or to stretch in any one position for more than a couple of relaxation breaths, but you will rarely hurt too much to stretch. Remember, stretching is one of the most important parts of the treatment that will help you heal. You must stretch to improve. If you are very uncomfortable, stretch more gently, not as far in any one position, and more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-should-i-call-my-doctor-for-an-emergency-visit&quot;&gt;When should I call my doctor for an emergency visit?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hurt too much to stretch, you need to call your doctor and return to the office for us to work on your body. Very often, we can help make your body stretch, even when you don’t seem able to. No matter how much pain you are experiencing, treatment doesn’t hurt as much as the discomfort you already feel. Additional treatment will help reduce your pain, and make it more possible for you to be able to follow your home program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-should-i-take-pain-medicine&quot;&gt;When should I take pain medicine?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain medication will help “take the edge off” the pain. Don’t expect complete relief and a pain free state after taking medication. Some people prefer not to take medication for pain. We have found that a natural response to pain is a tightening in the muscle. If the muscles tighten, you will hurt more. Taking medication can help reduce the tendency for this pain/tightening cycle to occur. Moderation is important, and your doctor will recommend how often medication should be taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;should-i-get-other-bodywork&quot;&gt;Should I get other bodywork?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After trigger point injections, the larger trigger points are much improved and fascia is looser. Chiropractic adjustment will be easier and hold longer. Massage therapy will usually smooth out the “kinks”. Additionally, with the tightest muscles released, the therapists will quickly be able to work on a deeper layer of tissue.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ryu Clinic</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Sections in this article</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
